<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Brendan</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Brendan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>More than One way to Skin your Code- A Prespective on Python and R</title>
      <link>/blog/a-prespective-on-python-and-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/a-prespective-on-python-and-r/</guid>
      <description>I was first introduced to computer programing through python. As I gradually became a better programer, I started working with R. At first I was bewildered by the languages high functionality and intricacies. Compared to python R seemed like a mess, unsure of what it really wanted to be. However, the more I became fimilar with R I realized it’s usefullness. Particulary, the R community is organized, connected, and receptive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 22:55:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description>Projects Here are some projects I have been working on:
 Project 1 Project 2  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 1: 2018 Storm Related Deaths</title>
      <link>/project1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project1/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionThe first data set I have choosen reports storm event details that happened in the United States in 2018, gathered by the NOAA. This data set contains a multitude of information such as time information, state, event type, culmintive injuries, culminative deaths, damage cost, and event type descriptors. The second dataset reports details for storm related deaths in 2018 also gathered by the NOAA. This dataset contains information for each indivdual death such as sex, age, fataility type, and loction description.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project2</title>
      <link>/project2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project2/</guid>
      <description>Brendan Panici
IntroductionThe thoracic surgery dataset contains a 17 descriptors for patients that underwent lung surgery for cancer in Poland between 2007 and 2011. There are 3 numeric variable forced vital capacity (FVC)(the total amount of air exhaled during the FEV test), FEV1 (the amount of air you can force from your lungs in one second), and age. The data set also contains 11 binary variables of which most are secondary phenotypes, such as smoking status.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>